There's a marketing trend that's existed for far too long now.
It's been years and it's more cringe than when all companies tried to use
Gangnam style to promote their brand.
It's this fixation on diluting all logos to just be bold text with the company name,
just this minimalist garbage where it removes all fun and whimsy and personality and
completely erases all creativity of logos and just reduces them to the company name
on a very bland color.
It's like the most sterile shit ever.
It's not interesting.
I think it's super sucks, but this has been the norm for a corpo dog shit for a while.
I still think the most infamous example is when staples made an entire E3 press conference
to unveil their new logo where they removed the iconic staples logo to make this and then
they had like paid shills in the audience going,
YAAAAAAAHH!
WEEEEEE!
All over like this staples logo unveiling, which again nobody cares about, it's a worst
logo.
All you've done is make a worst logo.
And now Cracker Barrel has finally followed suit where they redesigned their logo and
man did it hit them hard where it hurts the most, right?
And they're fucking precious nut sack of money.
Pretty much overnight they lost roughly $100 million in value.
Their stock took a nose dive into the shitter here.
And of course, plenty of people make the argument, it's just a logo, this is so overblown and
unnecessary.
It's not that big of a deal.
And I guess I can kind of understand that, but I also understand why so many people are
fed up with the inshitification of things.
Like, everything seems to be going in this direction where it gets boiled down to like
the same generic sludge where everything has to be the most bland, same-e-poup-ass.
Like it's just so unnecessary.
Like changing that logo and making it simpler does nothing.
For Cracker Barrel or for anybody, it's just a waste of diamond resources.
And there is more to it, it's not just the logo.
They are like redoing the menu, they're redoing the restaurants as well.
The idea is they want to make it the Cracker Barrel of today and tomorrow is the
verbiage that the CEO used.
She actually went and did an interview with Good Morning America where she affirms that
Cracker Barrel is really happy with how everything's going and that the response has actually
been overwhelmingly positive.
I don't know if they're just filter feeding her like five like tweets on Twitter that
are like, actually, she's good.
And they're like, yes, we're going in the right direction.
But they don't seem at all shocked or rocked or even slightly perturbed that their stock
has just nosed-dived after unveiling the new logo and the plans to like redesign and
redo certain elements of Cracker Barrel.
Well, remember, the heart and soul of Cracker Barrel is going to stay the same.
And so today we're actually launching a new campaign called All the More, which really
highlights how people feel about Cracker Barrel.
It's bigger than just a meal.
We've got a retail shop.
You're going to get great country hospitality with our scratch-made food and our restaurants.
And that's really what this campaign celebrates.
So we've enlisted a little bit of help from a guy named Jordan Davis.
Maybe you've heard of him.
He's got a new single and album out and he's in our ad and is the voice of it as well.
And it really again just highlights those things that make Cracker Barrel cracker rural.
I know everyone's all excited about Hollow Knight's silk song around the corner, but I tell
you what, I am chopping it a bit to get a piece of that Cracker Barrel ad campaign with
Jordan Davis being the hired spokesperson for it.
I can't wait.
That's exciting.
Yippee, thanks so much for sharing.
Basically, this whole interview is just trying to reassure people that the Cracker Barrel
they love is going nowhere, even though they are redoing the inside of the restaurant,
even though they are changing the menu and redoing some of the dishes, even though they are
changing the logo and even though they have redesigned their philosophy to be more about
the Cracker Barrel of the day and tomorrow as opposed to the Cracker Barrel of the past.
But other than that, like everything is exactly the same.
Is the food changing?
The food.
Well, here's what I'll say about that.
Innovation has proven to be really great at Cracker Barrel.
People are loving our new menu items.
We're reinvigorating our dinner menu.
And a lot of these, a lot of restaurants and leaning and going back to nostalgia, things
that the customer are really comfortable with.
We never left it.
You never left it, but you're changing up.
You're kind of going in a different direction.
Why is that your strategy?
Yeah, because the Cracker Barrel needs to feel like the Cracker Barrel for today and for tomorrow.
And again, the things that you love are still there.
We need people to choose us and we want people to choose us because people love this brand.
People love this brand, which is why we're changing it.
It feels really contradictory because this is all about her saying,
everything that makes Cracker Barrel of Cracker Barrel is going to stay the same.
We never left nostalgia, except we are leaving nostalgia.
We're modernizing.
Her whole, her whole spiel here, the entire pitch is about why the modernization of Cracker Barrel is a good thing.
And it's the right direction to go for the company.
The change in the menu, the new food, bringing back some old food.
She mentioned a meal is coming back.
Or I don't recognize the meal by name.
I've only been to Cracker Barrel like maybe 10 times in my life.
Actually, all of which have been a pretty decent dining experience.
I've never actually had a really bad time at Cracker Barrel.
It is kind of cute as this old, tiny experience.
But what she's insisting is that experience will still be there, but modernized.
But that clashes.
I don't know how you could modernize an old-school, old-style experience.
That would clash by its very nature, I would think.
If you're improving the food, great.
I never had any big complaints about the food at Cracker Barrel.
But if you want to introduce more high-quality cuisine options and just upgrade it,
that's fine by me.
Let it rip.
I just don't know why that also means you have to redesign the entire brand.
Identity and whatever.
To me, it reminds me of what video games have also been doing for a while now, which
I fucking hate.
And I'm always the first to spit on this, where a new entry into a franchise will have the
same name as another entry in the franchise.
And it grinds my ass so hard.
Like, Call of Duty Modern Warfare, Call of Duty Modern Warfare 2, and Call of Duty Modern
Warfare 3.
That's actually six games I just named right there.
Because there's two of each.
And they are so different.
So Call of Duty Modern Warfare is different from Call of Duty Modern Warfare.
Call of Duty Modern Warfare 2 is different from Call of Duty Modern Warfare 2.
Call of Duty Modern Warfare 3 is different from Call of Duty Modern Warfare 3.
Like, you see the problem?
Like, I hate that shit.
I hate that shit.
I'm going off on a different tangent.
Stop me now.
Stop me now before I start getting out of control with the ranting.
Point is, Cracker Barrel feels to me like it's doing that same thing where it's taking
Cracker Barrel and introducing Cracker Barrel 2025 on it.
Which is different.
But she's insisting that it's the same.
So what's the point in trying to present it as different?
Like just go ahead and make a marketing push that's like, hey, we upgrade our food, we
change these things around, we added new things to the gift shops and more modern items,
we repainted things inside to brighten it up, that kind of thing, whatever.
Another thing she mentioned is they're changing the chairs to make more comfortable chairs.
Big thumbs up for me.
I actually hated the chairs at Cracker Barrel sometimes.
My ass is a little bony.
So sitting on those chairs is a little uncomfortable for an extended period of time.
So changing the chairs there, great idea.
Does that also mean that it needs to come with like this whole push of like Cracker Barrel?
No, we've changed a little bit about everything.
I don't think so, but that's the trend of business these days where even like the slightest
change you need to introduce the sequel.
Like Overwatch.
Overwatch 2.
We've done almost nothing.
And we're calling it Overwatch 2.
This is the sequel.
It shit sucks.
It's just super useless.
Like that's kind of like the DNA that I feel from this Cracker Barrel logo change and
like this whole push about like the refreshing of Cracker Barrel.
I think ultimately it probably won't change that much, but they have changed the logo.
So immediately people will recognize it as something different, even if she's insisting
it's going to be the same experience.
And I think the logo is worse.
It follows another trend I hate of these really boring minimalist logos.
I think there's nothing fun or creative about it.
It sucks a lot of life out of a brand.
It just seems like a huge waste of resources to take a logo that everyone can immediately
identify and take everything out of it to just be the name and then try and present like
Cracker Barrel 2 is here.
This is the refresh.
But also it's like the exact same experience that you've always remembered.
Don't worry.
Everything you love about Cracker Barrel is still there.
Okay, well then why did you redo the logo and why are you calling it this huge refresh?
It just I don't know.
It feels super sloppy to me.
I'm not surprised to see people aren't really responding well to it.
It's worthless.
What if all the customers are coming at you hard enough about the look of the restaurant
and they want to go back to the old way?
Would you do it?
Honestly, the feedback's been overwhelmingly positive that people like what we're doing.
I'll give you another sound bite.
I actually happened to be in Orlando last week with all of our managers.
We bring them together and once every other year.
And the number one question that I got asked Michael was, how can I get a remodel?
When can I get a remodel?
How do I get on the list?
Oh really?
So because the feedback and the buzz is so good not only from our customers but from our
team members.
They want to work in a wonderful restaurant.
So sure, that's all fine and dandy.
But it is not really representative of everyone's perception of this redesign and this refresh.
Like you can anecdotally talk about the managers in Orlando shaking you like, when can we get
a remodel?
And use that as an indicator that you're going in the right direction.
But that doesn't tell the whole story.
Like I feel like, and of course I'm not in the board meeting here, but I feel like you
could point to the stock price correlating with when the logo design dropped.
And then also a couple with all of the feedback you could publicly see from everyone, including
your loyal customers, and probably make the assumption that maybe there's more people
unsatisfied with this than we're thinking.
Like they are currently writing it off as a vocal minority, but I feel like it's probably
a pretty large group of people that isn't really excited about this.
Of course, plenty of people that are upset about it are people that never read it Cracker
Barrel and probably never would have stepped foot in one in the first place.
But there also are definitely some customers that probably are a bit turned off here because
it's following the trend of every other business that is diluting everything that they've
built into just being like generic slop looking.
Even if that's not the case here with Cracker Barrel, people have already seen this song
and dance from plenty of other businesses over the years that a lot of people are just
tired of it in general.
Now what I will say is I don't think this will last long, not like the logo and everything
and the refresh, I'm sure they will fully commit to that and I'll probably be the norm
from this point going forward for Cracker Barrel for a long time.
What I don't think is going to last a while, what I think is a femoral, is people avoiding
Cracker Barrel in the stock plummeting.
I think this will fall the trend of most shit where once it stops being flavor of the
month, people will just go back to business as usual and they'll eat at Cracker Barrel
when convenient or with their grandparents or something like they're not going to be
canceling trips to Cracker Barrel a week from now.
So I'm sure it'll probably rebound to some extent or even completely.
Maybe it ends up being successful for them.
I don't know.
I just don't think it's going to stay like this from this point going forward.
But I guess I could be wrong about that.
Maybe people are just like, you know what?
Fuck Cracker Barrel for this and they're done with it.
That's possible.
I just find it unlikely because that almost never happens for any business really.
Anyway, I just wanted to app about this.
That's about it.
See ya.